Register of the Herbert Solow Papers 1924-1976
Hoover Institution Archives
- Subject File, 1930-1964.
  - Bronfenbrenner, Urie. Challenge of the `New Soviet Man,' The New York Times Magazine, August 27, 1961., Printed copy.
  - Brooks, Alexander, letter to Mrs. Henry A. Bellows, 1950., Carbon copy (typescript)
  - Buchanan, Thomas G. In defense of a theory, The New Leader, November 9, 1964., Printed copy.
  - Cannon, J. P., letter to Norman Mini, 1934., Carbon copy (typescript).
  - Cardona, Miro, a statement on his resignation from Cuban Exile Council, The New York Times, April 19, 1963., Printed copy.
  - Carter, Justice Edward F. Press clippings, Gering Courir, 1947-1948.
  - Castro, Fidel. Newspaper clippings, and articles about Castro.
  - Catholic Church - Doctrinal and controversial works.
  - Censorship - Military speeches. Newspaper clippings, articles.
  - Chambers, Whittaker. Periodical articles, newspaper clippings, correspondence about him., Printed and typewritten copies.
  - Chambers Whittaker, The faking of Americans, draft., Typewritten copy.
  - Civil rights - U.S.
  - Civil supremacy over the military.
  - Columbia College, Class of 1924.
  - Columbus Day United Anti-Fascist Committee, 1934. Open letter circular and an answer., Printed and typewritten copies.
  - Communists for Cultural Freedom.
  - Communist Party of the Soviet Union.
  - Communist
    - General
    - American
    - German
  - Coughlan, Robert, The tangled drama and private hells for two famous scientists, Title of periodical unknown, n.d., Printed copy.
  - Cuba (Box 6)
    - Foreign relations - U.S.
    - History-Invasion, 1961
    - Missile crisis
    - Politics and government, 1959-
  - Cuban Nickel Company
  - Dallin, David J. The first two stages Soviet designs in the Middle East, The New Leader, October 3, 1958., Printed copy.
  - Dealey, Ted
  - Decker, Carolyne
  - Declaration on German atrocities, October 30, 1943., Typewritten copy.
  - DePugh, Robert Bolicar
  - Dewey, John, William James' morals and Julien Benda's, Commentary, n.d., Printed copy.
  - Dominican Republic - Politics and government
  - Donovan, James B., The Nuernberg Trials, speech delivered to the Federal Bar Association, October 24, 1946., Mimeographed copy.
  - Douglas, Associate Justice William O. (U.S. Supreme Court), advance text of an address to be delivered October 28, 1946., Printed copy.
  - Draper, Theodore, Senator Fulbright's Cuban operation, and other articles, The New Leader, 1961, 1964., Printed copy.
  - DuBridge, L.A. Adventures in Space, and other articles, Engineering and Science, 1956-1961., Printed copies.
  - Dunmar, Cadet John H.
  - Duran, Gustavo
  - ECHO I Project, Press conference
  - Education - University of Chicago and Columbia University
  - Egypt - History - Intervention, 1956
  - Eichmann, Adolf
  - Eisenhower, Dwight D., President, U.S.
  - Erickson, Ralph W.
  - Evans, Walter
  - Faget, Colonel Mariano (Box 7)
  - Fahy, Charles, The Lawyer in Military Government (Germany) the American Bar Association, October 29, 1946., Printed copy.
  - Federal Writers' Project. Work Progress Administration. The National Capital, A chapter from the Guidebook Washington: City & Capital. Washington, G.P.O., 1937., Printed copy.
  - Finkelstein, Lawrence S. Testing in the atmosphere, The New Leader, February 19, 1962., Printed copy.
  - Flanders, Ralph E.
  - Forkosh, Morris D.
  - Fortune magazine, inter office memoranda, 1945-1960.
  - Fortune magazine articles, Comments on 1953-1962
  - Fortune magazine, Law Department
  - Frank, John P. Disqualification of judges, Yale Law Journal, 1947., Typewritten copy.
  - Frankel, Charles. Is it ever right to break the law? New York Times Magazine, January 12, 1964., Printed copy.
  - Freund, Arthur J.
  - Friends, List of
  - Fritzsche, Hans, convicted of war crimes
  - Fullbright, James William, U.S. Senator
  - Goldwater, Barry U.S. Senator
  - Government and the Press - U.S.
  - Greenfield, Meg. The Seattle settlement; a cold war nightmare, The Reporter, May 24, 1962., Printed copy.
  - Gregory, Tappan, Murder is murder and the guilty can be punished, American Bar Association Journal, September 1946., Printed copy.
  - Gross, John, John Bull & John Profumo, Commentary, August, 1963., Printed copy.
  - Guantanamo, Cuba - U.S. Naval Base
  - Guided missles
  - Hankey, Lord, address delivered at a Foyles literary lucheon at Drocherster Hotel, n.d., about his book, Politics, trials and errors., Printed copy.
  - Harbison, Frederick, Two centers of Arab power, Foreign Affairs, n.d., Printed copy.
  - Hauptmann, Gerhart, clipping, n.d.
  - Herman R. B., a receipt of letters, May 10, 1941.
  - Herndon, Angelo. Memoranda, speeches, letter to the editor, relative to Angelo Herndon's defense.
  - Himmler, Heinrich. File memorandum, January 31, 1939., Typewritten copy.
  - Hirota, Koki versus Douglas MacArthur, et al. Case at the U.S. Supreme Court, December 20, 1948.
  - Hirschman, Albert O. Second thoughts on the `Aliance for Progress,' The Reporter, May 25, 1961., Printed copy.
  - Hiss, Alger, clippings, articles, correspondence about
  - Hobson, Wilder, a letter of January 8, 1962.
  - Hogan, Frank S., a newspaper clipping, 1958.
  - Hook, Sidney, The cunning of history, published article, The New Leader, May 11, 1964., Printed copy.
  - I. G. Farben-Industrie, newspaper clippings, n.d.
  - Iasny, Naoum, Le Plan septennal en U.R.S.S. (in French), n.d., Printed copy.
  - Internal security - United States
  - International Labor Defense
  - International Labor Defense, 5th National Convention, Cleveland, Ohio, October 8-9, 1932.
  - International military tribunal (Box 8)
  - Israel
  - Israel - Emigration and immigration
  - Jackson, Justice Robert H.
  - Jamia'at al Islam, Inc.
  - Jews in Poland
  - John Birch Society
  - John Reed Club
  - Johnson, Lynden B., President of the U.S.
  - Kelley, Fred C. Why I am pro-Russian, a reprint from Digest and Review Magazine, originally copy-righted 1944, by Kiwanis Magazine., Printed copy.
  - Kennedy, Robert F., U.S. Attorney General, a biographical sketch
  - Kentucky coal fields, students' visit to
  - Kern County Land Company
  - Khrushchev, Nikita Sergeevich, Prime Minister of the U.S.S.R.
  - Khrushchev, Nikita S., On peaceful coexistence, published article, Foreign Affairs, October 1959., Printed copy.
  - Kline, George L., Education, published article, The New York Leader, June 16, 1958., Printed copy.
  - Kramer, Charles
  - Lafollette, Robert M.
  - Lamb, Edward, Trial by battle,'; the case history of a washington witch-hunt, a published occasional paper, April 1964., Printed copy.
  - Laos -- We may have to fight. July 18, 1961., Photocopy (typescript) Author unknown.
  - Lehrman, Hal, How the explosion was set off in Algeria, The Reporter, June 12, 1958., Printed copy.
  - Lemkin, Raphael, Genocide, The American Scholar, March 1946., Printed copy.
  - Leontief, Wassily, The decline and rise of Soviet economic science, Foreign Affairs, n.d., Printed copy.
  - Levine, Herbert S. Prospects for Russia's economic expansion, The New Leader, May 25, 1959., Printed copy.
  - Liberty of the press
  - Lichtfield, Edward H.
  - Lipson, Leon, The Gargarin and Powers flights, Bulletin of Atomic Scientists, n.d., Printed copy.
  - Lowe, James Trapier, Aviation and war, Air Affairs, September 1946, an excerpt from the article.
  - Luce, Henry R., Peace is the work of justice, an address delivered at the State Bar Association of Connecticut, October 23, 1956., Printed copy.
  - McCulloch, Warren S., M.D., Where is fancy bred? and other articles and lectures, 1960-1963., Printed copy.
  - McNamara, Robert S., newspaper clippings about him, New York Times, January 18, 1962.
  - Magnes, Judah L., For a Jewish-Arab confederation, Commentary, 1948., Printed copy.
  - Mallison, W. T., The incompatibility of the Zionist Israel legal claims to `The Jewish People' with the United States Constitution, summary of an address presented on May 11, 1962., Printed copy.
  - Mansure, Edmund F., newspaper clippings about and by him, 1955-1956.
  - Mexico - Foreign relations - U.S.
  - Mini, Norman
  - Mohrenschildt, George S. de, newspaper clippings
  - Mooney, Tom
  - Morley, Felix, How blindly must generals follow the leader? Barron's, May 7, 1951.
  - Mundt, Karl E.
  - Murphy, Charles J. V., America's widening military margin, Fortune, August 1957; Chiang, our embattled ally, Life, October 6, 1961; Cuba, the record set streight, Fortune, September 1961., Printed copies.
  - Nash, George and Patricia, The other witnesses, The New Leader, October 12, 1964., Printed copy.
  - National Committee for the Defense of Political Prisoners, 1933-1935
  - National Sacramento Appeal Committee, 1936
  - The National Student League, 1932
  - Near East (Box 9)
  - Niebuhr, Reinhold, Reflections on democracy as an alternative to communism, Columbia University Forum, Summer, 1961., Printed copy.
  - Nixon, Richard Milhouse, President of the U.S., newspaper clippings, 1962.
  - Nolte, Richard H. and Polk, William R., Toward a policy for the Middle East, Foreign Affairs, n.d., Printed copy.
  - Non-Partisan Labor Defense, 1934-1936
  - The Northwest Organizer, 1937
  - Novak, Alan R., Man, his dog and birth control: a study in comparative rights, reprinted from the Yale Law Journal, June 1961., Printed copy.
  - Nuremberg Novelty, Outline history of the, typewritten outline, February 5, 1947.
  - Nuremberg Trial of major German war criminals, 1945-1946.
    - General
    - Defendents' pleas
  - Nyaradi, Nicholas, 1950
  - Oil industries - Italy
  - Organization of American States
  - Origin of the war
  - Otrin, George W., Jr., Lieutenent, 2d
  - Outer space
    - General
    - Exploration
  - Packer, Herbert L., The Warren Report; a measure of achievement, The Nation, November 2, 1964., Photocopy of printing. (Box 10)
  - Palestine, 1930-1958.
  - Palmer, Ben W., The totalitarianism of Mr. Justice Holmes: another chapter in the controversy, American Bar Association Journal, November, 1951., Printed copy.
  - Pearson, Drew, JFK, press pal alike in views, newspaper clipping, n.d.
  - Peretz, Don, Arabs vs. Israelis: fiction and fact, Issues, Fall 1959.
  - Podolak, Hrihory
  - Powel, Samuel Wesley, Jr., Governor. Time, May 4, 1962
  - Poyntz, Juliet Stuart, 1935-1940
  - Puerto Rico, 1967
  - Punta del Este, Conference of... Newspaper clippings, 1962.
  - Rappleye, Willard, C. Jr., & Murphy, C. J. V., A notable fiscal recovery, Fortune, August 1960., Printed copy.
  - Razran, Gregory, Soviet psychology and psychophysiology, Science, November 1958., Printed copy.
  - Refugees
    - Arab
    - Cuban
    - Jewish
    - Political
  - Rickover, H. G., Vice-Admiral, USN
  - Right wing politicians
  - Rivkin, Arnold, Israel and the Afro-Asian world, Foreign Affairs, n.d., Printed copy.
  - Robins-Gras case, 1934
  - Roche, John P., The limits of Kennedy's libralism, The New Leader, October 1, 1962., Printed copy.
  - Roosevelt, Franklin D., President of the U.S.
  - Rostow, Eugene V., Success or disaster? Ike's foreign policy, The New Leader, November 22, 1954. Printed copy. The report of the Attorney General's Committee in perspective, remarks delivered at meeting of Antitrust Section, New York State Bar Association, January 26, 1956. Printed copy.
  - Sacco and Vanzetti
  - Sacramento criminal syndicalism cases, (reprint) International Juridical Association Bulletin, Nobember 1935.
  - Samish, Arthur A.
  - Schlamm, William S. Germany and the East-West Crisis, extract, n.d., Typewritten copy.
  - Schuman, F. L.
  - Scottsboro case
    - Untitled draft of an article. Author unknown.
    - Baldwin, Roger, 1935
    - Hernodon, Angelo, The Scottsboro boys, four freed, five to go, pamphlet, August, 1937., Printed copy.
    - Kirchwey, Freda, August 31, 1935
    - Non-Partisan Labor Defense. Executive Board. What next in Scottsboro? preliminary draft statement, n.d., Printed copy.
    - Scottsboro Defense Committee, December 19, 1935-March 16, 1936.
    - Scottsboro Defense Committee. What the Nation's Press says about the Scottsboro case,n.d., Printed copy.
    - Scottsboro Joint Committee, Conference, October 9, 1935
    - Shapiro, Morris, 1936
    - Thomas, Norman, July 31-August 31, 1937
  - Seabury, Paul, The histronaut, Columbia University Forum, Summer 1961., Printed copy.
  - Shapiro, Samuel, Doing good in Latin America; can the Alliance make fast enough progress? The New Republic, December 4, 1961., Printed copy.
  - Sherman, Alfred, The Paris meeting on Soviet Jewry, The New Leader, October 10, 1960., Printed copy.
  - Smith, Willis, The Nuremberg trials, American Bar Association Journal, July 1946., Typewritten copy.
  - Socialist Party of America, 1934-1935
  - Space flight to the moon
  - Space law
  - Spaniards in exile - Mexico - Political activities
  - Spector, Frank, The problems of United Front against boss terror, mimeographed statement, January 4, 1933
  - Spies (includes material on Ruth Marie Rubens) (Box 11)
  - Stevenson, Adlai, Ambassador to the U.N., newspaper clippings
  - Stimson, Henri L., The decision to use the atomic bomb, published article, Harper's Magazine, February 1947., Printed copy.
  - Stone, Harlan F., Chief Justice, U.S. Supreme Court, January 1946
  - Taylor, Maxwell, General, USA
  - Taylor, Telford, Arms and the Germans,1950, published article, Harper's Magazine, n.d., Printed copy.
  - Tiros I-IV
  - Tresca, Carlo
  - Trotsky Affair
    - American Committee for the Defense of Leon Trotsky, February - March 1937
    - Beard, Charles A., March 1937
    - Confidential memorandum, January 26, 1937
    - Trotsky, Committee for Asylum for... November 14, 1934
    - Trotsky, Natalia Sedow, December 1949
  - Truman, Harry, S., President, United States, newspaper clipping, September 16, 1963
  - U-2 Incident, 1960
  - United Fruit Company, April 15, 1959
  - U.S. Airforce, newspaper clippings
  - U.S. Army - Public relations, March 4, 1948
  - U.S. Central Intelligence Agency, 1961-1962
  - U.S. Federal Bureau of Investigation
  - U.S. - Foreign relations - Russia
  - U.S. - Politics and government
  - U.S. President. Report to Congress. United States Aeronautics and Space Activities, 1961. January 1962., Printed copy.
  - U.S. Senate. Committee on Armed Services. Preparedness Investigating Sub-Committee. The B-70 report.1960., Printed copy.
  - U.S. Supreme Court, 1952-1959.
  - Van Fleet, James A., General, U.S. Army (Ret.) newspaper clippings, n.d. (Box 12)
  - Wald, Alan, The Menorah Journal moves left, essay, n.d., Photocopy (typescript)
  - Walker, Edwin A., Major General, U.S. Army
  - Ward, Barbara, A direction for the West, Saturday Review, January 27, 1962., Printed copy.
  - Wechsler, Herbert, The issues of the Nuremberg Trial, address read December 30, 1946;Remarks before a showing of the film Nuremberg -- its lesson for today, an address, December 28, 1950., Printed copies.
  - Weinstein, Allen
  - Wennerstrum affair, (Judge Charles, F. Wennerstrum presiding judge of the Southeast Generals Nuremberg war crime trial) February 28, 1948, mimeographed.
  - Whitney, Thomas P., The U.S. and the Dominicans, The New Republic, February 12, 1962., Printed copy.
  - Wohlforth, Robert Martin, U.S. Senator
  - Wolfson, Richard F. Review of The case of General Yamashita, by A. Frank Reel. Chicago, U, of Chicago Press, 1939. Pp. vi, 324, in The Yale Law Journal, Vol. 59 (January 1950), 384-5., Printed copy.
  - Wyzanski, Charles E., Jr., The Nuremberg war criminals trial, a printed communication to the American Academy of Arts and Sciences, December 12, 1945., Printed copy.
  - Zionism
  - Zionist Organization of Roumania
- Miscellany, 1932-1965
  - Clippings (Box 12)
  - Scrapbook of newspaper clippings relative to: communism, labor, naziism, politics and government, etc.